# Curriculum Vitae

**RIA SARKAR** 

Email: sarkarria90@gmail.com

Contact: 8017593515

LinkedIn:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/ria-sarkar-

b71097b9

# **Career objective**

My motto is to keep learning and to work with honesty and integrity in a creative and globally competitive environment, where I can utilize my experience and skills in contributing effectively to the success of the organization and also for the improvement of my personal skills.

#### **Education**

Name of the Institution	Name of the exam	Board	Year of passing
St. Stephen's School. Dumdum	I.C.S.E	I.C.S.E	2007
St. Paul's K.G and Day School	I.S.C	I.S.C	2009

## Interest

- Listening to music.
- Traveling.
- Cooking.

# Skillsets

- Talent Acquisition
- Recruitment
- Sourcing
- Screening
- Scheduling Interviews
- Documentation
- Naukri, LinkedIn, Indeed

### **Experience**

#### **Recruitment Specialist (Domestic Staffing)**

Pride Circle (Inclusion First Consultancy Pvt. Ltd.) – April 2023 to Present

- Responsible to make verification calls to the registered candidates.
- Taking calls from customers/vendors queries or complaints and escalating the issues to the concerned team.
- Sourcing resumes from the Internal Database, make screening calls to candidates for a particular role and submitting their profiles to the clients and Job Posting on LinkedIn.

#### **Corporate Recruiter (US Staffing)**

Spectraforce Technologies Pvt. Ltd. – November 2021 to December 2022

- Responsible to hire IT and Non-IT Recruiters for US Recruitment.
- Screening resumes, Job posting on LinkedIn, Naukri to attract candidates.
- Performing phone interviews with candidates.
- Administering appropriate company assessments.
- Coordinating interviews with the hiring managers.
- Following up on the interview process status.
- Performing pre-on boarding process like salary discussion, negotiation, documentation.
- Communicating employer information and benefits during screening process.
- Completing timely reports on employment activity.

#### **Corporate Recruiter (US Staffing)**

Techaxis, Inc. – December 2020 to May 2021

- Screening resumes, Job posting on LinkedIn, Naukri to attract candidates.
- Performing in-person and phone interviews with candidates.
- Administering appropriate company assessments.
- Performing reference and background checks.
- Making recommendations to company hiring managers.
- Coordinating interviews with the hiring managers.
- Following up on the interview process status.
- Communicating employer information and benefits during screening process.
- Completing timely reports on employment activity.

#### Nerine Infosolutions Pvt. Ltd. – January 2018 to November 2018

- Responsible for end-to-end recruitment from sourcing, short listing, screening
  profiles from different job portals according to the requirement of the
  company.
- Conducting Telephonic rounds followed by face to face rounds of interview with the candidates.
- Job role included selection/rejection, salary negotiation, joining formalities, documentation of the selected candidates.
- Ensuring closure of the requirements within the given period of time by the company.

#### **HR Executive (International BPO)**

Alenam Technologies Pvt. Ltd. – July 2016 to December 2017

- Responsible for end-to-end recruitment from sourcing, short listing, screening profiles from different job portals according to the requirement of the company.
- Conducting Telephonic rounds followed by face to face rounds of interview with the candidates.
- Job role included selection/rejection, salary negotiation, joining formalities, documentation of the selected candidates.
- Ensuring closure of the requirements within the given period of time by the company.

#### **HR Recruiter (Consulting Services)**

Tutelage Solutions Pvt. Ltd. – February 2015 to December 2015

- Responsible for end-to-end recruitment from sourcing, short listing, screening
  profiles from different job portals according to the requirement of the client.
- Conducting Telephonic rounds of interview with the candidates.
- Ensuring closure of the requirements within the given period of time.

#### **Personal Details**

Name: Ria Sarkar

Date of birth: 12th July 1990

Father's Name: Ashim Sarkar

Languages known: English, Bengali, Hindi.

Address: 19/53, Mall Road, Kolkata - 700080.

I hereby declare that the information furnished above is true to the best of my knowledge.

Date:	Ria Sarkar